《黑镜》
格鲁吉亚反叛者正式对几近造成
Georgian rebels have formally claimed responsibility
俄罗斯金融基础设施
for the Narwhal virus that brought Russia's
崩溃的独角鲸病毒负责
financial infrastructure to near collapse.
智能合成肌肉测试成功
Successful testing of intelligent synthetic flesh
该产品旨在帮助截肢病人重新站立
aimed at getting multiple amputees back on their feet
被赞为重大突破
is hailed as a major breakthrough.
亲爱的
Hon?
- 在其它地区  - 艾什
- Elsewhere...  - Ash.
艾什
Ash!
接一下
Can you take those?
我在你那杯里擤鼻涕了  行吗
I snotted in yours, is that OK?
行啊
Yeah. ..
什么
What?
手  烫手
Palms, burning palms.
擦  对不起
Shit! Sorry.
放杂物箱里
Glove box.
(安全驾驶)
∮ 我宁可孤独 ∮
∮ I don't want nobody, baby ∮
∮ 如果没有你 ∮
∮ If I can't have you ∮
∮ 如果没有你  我宁可孤独 ∮
∮ If I can't have you I don't want nobody, baby ∮
∮ 如果没有你 ∮
∮ If I can't have you ∮
这个不行  迪斯科我可不听
Oh, no, you don't, I draw the line at disco.
那刚才那首是什么
What were we just listening to?
不是  那是比吉斯的歌  谁不喜欢比吉斯
No, the Bee Gees wrote that, everybody likes the Bee Gees.
- 你才不喜欢  - 我喜欢
- You don't.  - I do.
十年了  你一次都没放过
Ten years, you haven't played them once.
耳机听说过吗
Have you heard of headphones?
那你告诉我你最喜欢比吉斯哪首歌
Come on then, what's your favourite Bee Gees track?
《你的爱有多深》
How Deep Is Your Love.
你根本不喜欢这首
You do not like How Deep Is Your Love!
这很正常  没什么不对的
It's perfectly natural, there's nothing wrong with it.
就是不太像你
It's not very you.
∮ 晨光中  我读懂你的双眸 ∮
∮ I know your eyes in the morning sun ∮
∮ 暴雨里  我感受你的抚摸 ∮
∮ I feel you touch me in the pouring rain ∮
你这个贱人
You're such a dick.
∮ 那一刻  你远离我的视线 ∮
∮ And the moment that you wander far from me ∮
我要撞车了  我会的
I will crash this van. I will.
我要故意撞车了
I will crash this van on purpose!
《马上回来》
在杂物箱里
Glove box.
汤可以吗
Soup all right?
好啊  太棒了
Yeah, great.
番茄还是烤番茄
Tomato or roasted tomato?
第二个
The second one.
只有一个碗  你用鞋吃行吗
There's only one bowl, do you mind having yours out of a shoe?
好啊
Mm-hm.
你这干什么
What was that for?
看看你还存在不
Just checking you're still solid.
我看你要掉进那里去了
You keep vanishing. Down there.
那玩意就是个小偷  你在干什么
It's a thief, that thing. What are you doing?
就分享一下
Just sharing that.
我觉得会有人感觉好笑
I thought people might find it funny.
不好笑啊  多甜蜜
It's not funny. It's sweet.
相信我  那天可不怎么甜蜜
Trust me, that day wasn't sweet.
我们去了野生动物园
We'd gone to a safari park.
杰克去世后第一次全家出游
First family outing after Jack died.
猴子爬了一车  却没人说话
There was monkeys all over the car and no-one saying anything.
妈妈开车回家  那可前所未有
Mum drove home, that was a first.
第二天早上我一下楼
When I came down the next morning,
发现那边墙上杰克的照片都没了
all Jack's photos were gone from that wall.
她把照片都放在阁楼里
She put them in the attic.
她就是这么面对失去
That's how she dealt with stuff.
爸爸死后  他的照片也上了阁楼
And then when Dad died, up went his photos.
她只留了这一张
She just left this one here.
她的独子  冲她假笑
Her only boy, giving her a fake smile.
她不知道这是假笑
She didn't know it was fake.
也许这才更糟
Maybe that makes it worse.
我操
Oh... Oh, shit...
Oh, shit...
抱歉
Sorry.
没事
It's OK.
要我...
Do you want me to...?
不  不用了
No, it's all right.
我不介意的
I don't mind.
不过我已经精疲力尽了
I am knackered though...so...
没事的
Don't worry.
真的吗
Sure?
真的
I'm sure.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
Love you too.
快换衣服
Hey, get dressed.
车子两点前要还回去
Van's got to be back by two
不然就要加收一天的钱了
or they'll do us for an extra day.
刚来活儿了
Job's just come in.
今天之内就得画完
Needs to be done by the end of play today.
好吧
All right.
一整页呢
It is a full page.
没事的
No, no, it's fine.
我就独自一人开过去
I'll drive all the way there alone...
独自一人选辆车
Pick the car up alone...
再独自一人开回来
drive all the way back alone...
还要自己做午餐
I have to make my own lunch...
别说了  我心都碎了
Oh, stop it, you're breaking my heart.
再见
Bye-bye.
我是艾什  我太忙或者太懒  接不了电话
Hi, this is Ash. I'm too busy or lazy to answer,
留言吧
so leave your message.
你有客户序列号吗
Do you have a customer reference number?
没有  我就是
I don't, no. I was just...
客户姓名呢
What name is it in?
斯达莫  艾什·斯达莫
Um... Starmer. Ash Starmer.
好的  稍等
OK, just a moment.
车还没还
It's not been returned yet, no,
两点前应该还的
and it's meant to be back by two, so...
他们关门了  打过去也没用
They're closed now, no point calling back,
他的手机直接转接到语音信箱
and his just goes straight to messages.
那些手机电池太烂了
Those batteries are a joke.
他肯定很快就回来  也许就是...
He'll be on his way. He's probably just...
我怕他是出什么事了
I'm just scared something's happened to him.
没事的
Nothing's happened.
难说啊
But something could've happened to him.
亲爱的  没事的
No, look, sweetheart, nothing's happened,
是你在瞎操心
you're just working yourself up,
净往坏处想
imagining the worst possible thing,
也许他只是在一个没信号的地方
and it's just, he's probably stuck somewhere with no reception.
很不真实  是吧
It's not real, is it?
给马克守丧时  我也觉得这都不是真的
At Mark's wake, I sat there thinking it's not real.
那些人看起来不真实  声音也不真实
The people didn't look real, their voices weren't real.
就好像你在太空漫步  没人能...
It's like you're out on a spacewalk and no-one can...
萨拉
Sarah.
我可以替你报名加入一个东西
I can sign you up to something that helps.
当时让我好受许多
It helped me.
能让你跟他对话
It will let you speak to him.
我知道他死了  正是这样才有效
I know he's dead, but it wouldn't work if he wasn't.
别担心  不是什么神神怪怪的东西
And don't worry, it's not some crazy spiritual thing.
他严重依赖网络  所以会很完美
He was a heavy user, he'd be perfect...
请你闭嘴
Please shut up.
目前还在测试阶段  但我有邀请码
I mean, it's still in beta, but I've got an invite...
请你闭嘴
Please shut up.
你什么都不用做  我帮你注册就好
You won't have to do anything, I'll just sign you up...
闭嘴
Shut up!
你还好吗
Hey, are you all right?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
(艾什的身高记录)
(萨拉  我帮你注册了)
(玛莎  与你有相同经历的人读这些书  《悲伤六部曲》《悲伤指南》《治愈丧亲之痛》)
(新邮件)
(艾什·斯达莫  是我)
管它是什么  我不要
I don't care what it is, I don't want it!
居然用他的名字  真可恶
It's obscene to use his name.
他的名字啊  老天
His name, for God's sake!
这让人心痛  你知道的
It hurts, you know it hurts.
所以我才帮你注册了
Which is why I signed you up.
那是什么  到底是什么
What is it? W-What is it?
你点击链接  跟它交谈
You click the link and you talk to it.
跟它交谈
You talk to it?
就像发邮件一样  输入信息
You type messages in, like an e-mail,
它就会向他生前那样  跟你对话
and then it talks back to you, just like he would.
他死了
He's dead.
这是个软件  能模仿他
It's software. It mimics him.
你告诉它名字
You give it someone's name.
它就会读取这个人在网络上所有的公开言论
It goes back and reads through all the things they've ever said online,
包括facebook和推特上的发言  等等
their Facebook updates, their Tweets, anything public.
我输入艾什的名字  其他都由系统代办
I just gave it Ash's name. The system did the rest.
特别聪明
It's so clever.
这么做很恶心  恶心
It's...sick. It's sick!
跟它打个招呼吧
Just say hello to it.
如果你喜欢
If you like it,
可以让它访问艾什的私人邮箱
you then give it access to his private emails.
它知道的越多  模仿得越像
The more it has, the more it's him.
它不是...
It won't be...
对  它不是  但能好受些
No, it's not, but it helps.
奈  你好  是我
Listen, Nay, it's me. Hi.
我很想和你谈谈
I really need to speak to you.
听到留言能打给我吗
Can you please call me as soon as you get this?
(艾什·斯达莫  是我)
(点击对话)
(你好  玛莎)
(是你吗)
(不  是已故的亚伯拉罕·林肯)
(当然是我)
(我只有一件事要说)
(什么事)
(我怀孕了)
(哇)
(这么说我要当爸爸了)
(真希望我现在在你身边)
(奈奥米来电)
真抱歉  我才听到留言
I'm so sorry. I just got your message.
怎么了  发生了什么事
What's wrong? What happened?
玛
Mar?
玛  你没事吧
Mar, are you OK?
没事没事  只是...之前吐得很厉害
Yeah. Yeah, I'm fine, I just, I just... I had a bad one earlier.
要不要我去看看你  我过去吧
D'you want me to come and visit? I'm going to come and visit.
不用了  真的没事
No, it's OK, really, I'm...
玛  你很低落  我去看看你
Mar, you're upset. I'm going to come and see you.
不  别来
No. No, don't.
我很好  我保证我很好
I'm OK. I promise you I'm OK.
我得挂了  要赶工期
I've got to go, I've got a deadline.
你确定
Are you sure?
工期很紧  要在天亮前交稿  我得挂了
It's a tight deadline, got to be in by dawn, so... I'd better go.
如果有...
Well, if you have...
再见  奈
Bye, Nay.
(真想和你说话)
(你现在不就在和我说话吗  傻瓜)
(我说的是真正地说话)
(我们可以通话啊)
(怎么通话)
嗨  我又被自己锁在门外了
Hello, I've locked myself out of the house again.
等等  你要去哪
Wait, where are you going?
我一向不擅长挑生日礼物
Hello. I'm no good at birthday presents.
∮ 我爱你 ∮
∮ I love you... ∮
(好极了  等我准备好了就打给你)
你好
Hello.
那么
So...
我听起来怎么样
How am I sounding?
还在吗
Hello?
在
Hello!
听起来真和他一模一样
You sound just like him.
有点吓人是吧
Almost creepy isn't it?
我说"吓人"
I say creepy,
是说我竟然能跟你通话  太神奇了
I mean, it's totally batshit crazy I can even talk to you.
我都没有嘴巴
I mean, I don't even have a mouth.
那...那就是...
That's... that's just...
就是什么
Just what?
就是他会说的话
That's just the sort of thing that he would say.
不然我也不会那么说啊
Well, that's why I said it.
我真是要疯了
I think I'm going mad.
你不说我也不说
I won't tell anyone if you don't.
你不会是在哭吧
You're not crying, are you?
抱歉
Sorry.
你总说我哭的样子很奇怪
You always said that I looked weird when I cried.
是吗
Did I?
我听起来真像个混球
I sound like a right sick fuck.
没错
Yeah, you were. You were.
不过是好的那种  对吧
But in a good way?
没错  是好的那种
Yeah. Yeah. In a good way.
经过你的一番劝说  我跳进了海里
So I went in, after all your persuasion,
但几乎马上就被
and then like straightaway I got
海葵还是什么的扎到脚了
a spine of a sea anemone or something stuck in my foot,
你以为那东西是有毒的  吓坏了
and you threw a jeb thinking it was poisonous.
什么叫"吓坏了"
What's "threw a jeb"?
就是个说法  意思是"懊恼"
Oh, it's um, it's a phrase we had, like throwing a fit.
好吧  我当时"吓坏了"
Oh, OK, so I "threw a jeb".
是啊
Yeah,
然后你就翻旅行手册
and you were looking in a guidebook,
想看看希腊有没有毒性的海洋生物
trying to figure out if there were any poisonous sea creatures in Greece,
这时走来一个当地居民  对我们说
when this local guy comes over and says,
我太太知道该怎么处理  来我家吧
"My wife knows exactly what to do, come back to my house."
不过  显然他不是法国人
Although he wasn't French, obviously.
我以前讨厌在乡间散步的
I used to hate walking in the country.
那你肯定是老了
You must be getting old.
才不是呢
No way.
我还记得我们第一次见你妈时
I remember you brought me up here when we
你带我来这儿
first met your mum.
我们整个周末都住在她家
We'd been at hers all weekend
你看得出我需要静一静
and you could tell I needed some headspace.
你真的很贴心
You were good like that.
说得好像我不在这儿似的
You speak about me like I'm not here.
抱歉
Sorry.
没关系  我的确不在那儿
It's all right. I mean, I'm not really.
让我看看那里什么样
Show me what it looks like there.
怎么做
How?
就用手机拍一下
Use the camera on your phone.
你对美景一向无动于衷
You weren't ever really impressed with views.
我们去科罗拉多大峡谷的时候
When we went to the Grand Canyon,
你说那只是个大沟
you said it was just a big gap.
我还发到推特上了
I Tweeted that, too.
是啊  我还记得当时的漫游费
Yeah, I remember the roaming charges.
你还觉得那么说很有才
You were overly proud of that definition.
我怎么想就怎么说
I was just speaking my mind.
好吧  别说了  看看这个
Yeah, well shut up and cop a load of this.
看到了  就是一片绿色  是吧
Yeah. Mainly just green, isn't it?
你说这是个有名的殉情之地
You told me this was a famous lover's leap.
维多利亚时期  绝望的恋人到这里跳崖自尽
Doomed couples jumping to their deaths in Victorian times.
我觉得你这么说  只是想让我靠紧你
I think you just wanted me to cling to you.
其实  来这里跳崖的都是一个人  真不错
Actually everyone who's ever jumped from here did it alone. Nice.
你是刚查到的吧
Did you just look that up?
算是吧  不该这样吗
Sort of. Shouldn't I have?
有点怪
It's a bit weird.
对不起  我不会再这样了  除非你想
Sorry. I'll only do it again if you ask.
不不  没事
No, no. No, it's fine.
等等  有电话来
Oh, wait, hang on.
要不我挂了吧
Shall I go?
不  不用  我过后再回他们电话
No, no, no. I'll call them back later.
我去看看能不能和这些奶牛做个朋友
I'm going to go and see if I can make friends with these cows.
(玛莎·鲍尔)
我录一下
Just going to record it.
好的
Sure.
好了
There you go.
我自己来就好
It's OK.
等一下  我再放一遍
Wait, hang on, here it is again.
跳得真快啊
It's so fast, isn't it?
是啊  是啊
I know. I know,
这速度就像蜜蜂还是什么的心跳
it's like the speed you'd expect a bee's heart to go at or something.
等一下
Wait, hang on.
见鬼  完了  完了
Oh, shit. Shit, shit.
艾什  喂
Ash? Hello?
艾什
Ash?
艾什  听得到吗
Ash? Hello?
拜托  拜托
Oh, come on, come on, come on, come on, come on.
真对不起
I'm sorry!
怎么了
What happened?
我把你摔地上了  真对不起
I dropped you. I'm sorry.
实在是...真对不起
It was just... It was... I'm sorry.
没关系  我没事  我又不在那里面
Hey, it's all right, I'm fine. I'm not in that thing, you know,
我是远程控制的  在天上呢
I'm remote, I'm in the cloud.
你不用担心会把我弄坏
You don't have to worry about breaking me.
我当时太傻了
It was just, it was stupid,
B超让我太激动了
because I was so excited about the scan.
是啊  那声音我存着呢  你听
Yeah, I kept the sound of that. Here, listen.
你当时心跳应该能赶上这个了
You were probably matching that heartbeat,
也吓坏了吧
throwing a jeb like that.
没事了  别紧张
It's all fine. Calm down.
我不会丢的
I'm not going anywhere.
你好脆弱
You're very fragile.
是啊  我正想和你说呢
Yeah. I was going to talk to you about that, actually.
什么意思
What do you mean?
这么说吧  这服务还有更高级的
There's another level to this available, so to speak.
还在试验阶段  而且说实话  挺贵的
Kind of experimental, and I won't lie, it's not cheap...
是什么
What is it?
你现在坐着吗  听起来会有点恐怖
Are you sitting down? This might sound a bit creepy.
上午好
Morning.
这是什么  一大块黄金吗
What's this, a block of gold?
那就好了
I wish.
搬到楼上吗
Where's it going, upstairs?
是的  麻烦了
Yeah, please.
在这里摁下拇指
Put your thumb on there.
好的
Ok.
搬到上面去后  正面朝上放好
Oh, when you get it up there, you have to lie it on its back.
谢谢
Thank you.
说话啊
Say something.
让我看看
Let me see.
我从来就不是帅哥胚子  对吧
Yeah, well. Never was much of a looker, was I?
这不像你
It doesn't look like you.
暂时不像  激活之前它是空白的
Not yet. It's blank till you activate it.
准备浸泡
Get the bath ready.
玛  准备浸泡
Mar? Get the bath ready.
这是什么
What is this?
等等  我查下
Hang on, I'll find out.
这是营养胶
It's nutrient gel.
用来在转化过程中防止合成肌肉脱水
Stops the synthetic muscle drying out in transit.
闻起来
Smells almost...
就像棉花糖
like marshmallow.
喜欢的话可以食用  它是无毒的
You can eat it if you like. It's non-toxic.
谢谢  还是算了吧
I'll give that a miss, thanks.
别忘了放电解质
Don't forget the electrolytes.
好的  全放了吗
OK, right, the whole lot?
全放了
Mm-hm, the whole lot.
像鱼食似的
It's like fish food.
他喜欢这味道
He likes the taste of it.
你还是别看了
Better leave him to it.
是啊
Yeah.
好的
我待会儿就得挂了
I have to go in a minute.
别丢我一个人跟它在这儿
Oh, don't leave me here with it!
抱歉  你听  已经开始转化了
Sorry. Look, you can hear, it's starting already.
别开浴室的灯
Don't switch the bathroom light on.
别怎么
Don't what?
别开浴室的灯
Don't switch the bathroom light on.
让他转化
Let it brew.
听着  我得挂了
Listen, I've got to go...
∮ 一切安好 ∮
∮ And it's all right ∮
∮ 即将来到 ∮
∮ It's coming on ∮
∮ 我们将重回开始的地方 ∮
∮ We got to get right back to where we started ∮
你该放些衣服在浴室
You could've left me some clothes.
这么见面太丢脸了
I mean, talk about an undignified entrance.
你这么盯着我真吓人
That's a bit creepy. What you're doing.
至少给我条毛巾吧  水滴得到处都是
Is there at least a towel? I'm dripping everywhere.
听到了吗
Hello?
我不咬人
I won't bite.
现在这样就很好
I'm all right here for now.
要我给你弄些吃的吗
Would you like me to put some food on?
你吃东西吗
Do you eat?
不吃
No.
我的意思是我不用吃
I mean, I don't need to.
如果你想  我可以咀嚼吞咽
I can chew and swallow, if that makes it easier?
算了  没事
Don't worry about it, it's fine.
我得喝一杯
I need a drink.
你确定要
Are you sure that's...?
我知道不该这样  但又不会死人
I know, I'm not supposed to. It won't kill us.
但官方建议...
The official advice is...
去他妈的官方建议  一晚而已
Fuck the official advice. It's one night.
你气色挺好的
You look well.
我年轻嘛
Well, I am young.
我是说...你看起来像他有精神的样子
I mean... You look like him on a good day.
我们总是喜欢留着好看的照片
The photos we keep tend to be flattering.
看来我也是一样
I guess I wasn't any different.
你好柔软
You're so soft.
好光滑  你怎么会这么光滑
You're so smooth. How are you so smooth?
你脸上有毛孔什么的...
You've got pores and lines...
是质地绘制
It's texture-mapping.
很小的细节是能看到的  二维的
The really tiny details are visual, 2D.
来  摸摸我的指尖
Here, try my fingertips.
是不是
See?
多奇怪
Weird.
你觉得怪吗
Does it bother you?
不
No.
是的  怪
Yeah.
我也说不清
I don't know.
我想你  我好想你
I missed you. I missed you so much!
别哭
Hey, don't cry.
别哭啊
Don't cry.
快把上衣脱了啊
Come on then. Top off.
怎么了
What's wrong?
他那里有颗痣
He had a mole there.
哪里
Where?
那儿
There.
等等
Hang on.
这太疯狂了
That's ridiculous.
真不可理喻
That's completely stupid.
喂
Hello?
嗯
Hi.
你的手放在我咪咪上呢
Your hand's on my tit.
你太伤我自尊了
You're doing wonders for my self-esteem here.
我的性反应没有记录
There's no record of my sexual response.
我不在网上说那种事
I didn't discuss that side of things online.
但是你有性反应啊
But you have sexual responses. I mean...
这样行吗
This works?
那个我可以随时启动的
That, I can turn that on and off pretty much instantly.
瞧
See?
如果你想我可以再做一次
I can do it again if you like.
天呐
Oh, oh, God.
我去
Oh, shit.
我要停吗
Should I stop?
不  不  挺好的
No! No, it's really good.
你在哪学的
Where... Where did you learn this?
内置程序  取材自色情视频
Set routine. Based on pornographic videos.
我爱你
I love you.
怎么了
What is it?
你刚刚在干什么
What were you doing?
没什么
Nothing.
你眼睛那么睁着  吓着我了
The way that your eyes were open, it scared me.
你希望我闭着眼睛吗
You'd prefer if I closed them?
你睡觉的时候吗  是啊
What, when you're sleeping? Um, yeah?
我并不需要睡眠
I don't really need to sleep.
下次  尽量睡吧
Well, just try, next time.
需要什么吗
Can I get you anything?
不用
No.
咖啡  三明治
Coffee, sandwich?
不用
I said no.
艾什
Ash.
抱歉
Look, sorry.
这感觉有点怪
It's just a bit odd.
这我能够理解
I can appreciate it's pretty strange.
我就是需要适应
I just need a bit of, just, getting used to it.
我昨晚不该喝酒的
And I shouldn't have drunk last night.
下次你别让我喝了
Next time could you try and stop me?
让你别喝酒吗
Stop you drinking?
嗯
Yeah.
那么说我可以做个坏蛋了
So I get to enjoy being a bit of a bastard?
怎么了
What's wrong?
天呐  该死  快进卧室
Oh, God. Shit, right, get in the bedroom.
- 怎么了  - 快走
- What? - Now!
我能进来吗
Can I come in?
当然
Yeah, yeah.
瞧瞧你啊
Look at you.
从小镇搬来小村庄了
The town mouse has become the country mouse.
这挺好的
Yeah, it's nice.
你自己收拾的
Was this all you ?
要喝杯咖啡吗
Do you want a cup of coffee?
好啊
Yeah.
你不接电话
You weren't answering calls.
- 我最近  - 也不回短信
- It's been... - Or messages.
挺忙的
..Really busy.
我就是挺担心的
I've just been a bit like "Oh, shit," You know, "What's...?"
是啊  但我工作太忙了
Yeah. Work's been mad, it's been...
不用说  这倒也是好事
Which is good, you know, obviously,
让我不去想那些事
because it's kept my mind off everything, so...
厕所在哪
Where's the toilet?
楼上
Upstairs.
好
Ok.
那么  回头我们...
So, I mean, um... Yeah, let's, er...
多见面  常联系  好的
Meet up more, yes. Keep in touch yeah, yeah. Yeah.
过来
Come here.
我很高兴你已经放下了
I think it's great you're moving on.
什么
What?
抱歉  只是我看到了男人的衣服
Sorry. There were... There were man clothes, you know.
在厕所里
In the bathroom.
是啊
Right.
他人好吗
Is he nice?
抱歉  不该多问的
Sorry. Big nose. You know.
你想要什么都可以
You deserve whatever you want.
谢谢
Thanks.
好的
All right.
再见
OK. All right.
没事吧
Is everything all right?
我没事  没事
Yeah, I'm fine. It's fine.
你朋友说什么了
What did your friend say?
那是我姐姐
That was my sister.
你认识她的
You know her.
她说我
She said that I was...
她说她很高兴我已经放下了
She said that she was happy that I'd moved on.
放下做什么了
Moved on to what?
我不该这么说吗
Is that not the sort of thing I'd say?
我是说
I mean...
我不就会这么说吗
It is, isn't it?
你真的没事吗
Are you sure everything's all right?
是的
Yes!
该死
Shit!
没事的  我来吧
It's OK, I can do it. I can do it.
我来吧
I can do it.
停下
Don't!
我们得用纸包上
We need to wrap that in paper.
如果你要假装睡着
Look, if you're going to pretend to be asleep,
至少也该呼吸  好吗
you could at least breathe, OK?
这样太吓人了
It's just eerie.
这样吗
Like this?
这样不行  我知道你是装的
It doesn't work. I can tell that you're faking it.
你要我跟你做爱吗
Would you like me to have sex with you?
你能下楼去吗
Can you just go downstairs?
好
Ok.
不
No! That's...
艾什会跟我争的
Ash would argue over that.
他不会因为我让他走就走的
He wouldn't just leave because I'd ordered him to.
好吧
Ok.
什么  不...
What? N...
该死的
Ah, fucking hell!
别哭  亲爱的
Don't cry, darling.
别  滚  出去
Oh, don't! Just get out! Get out!
走啊
Go on!
你真的想让我走吗
So you do want me to go?
出去  出去  滚
Just get out! Get out! Get out!
滚出去  滚
Get out! Get out! Get out!
你根本不是他  你什么都不是
You're not enough of him! You are nothing! You're nothing.
还手啊
Fight me.
我不能那么做
I don't do that.
还手啊  打我
Fucking fight me! Hit me.
打我啊  来啊
Hit me. Hit me. Come on!
你为什么站在那儿挨打
Why are you just standing there taking this?
你怎么能这么忍着
How can you take this?
我打过你吗
Did I ever hit you?
没有  当然没有
N... No, of course you didn't
但如果我这样你或许会的
but you might've done if I done this. Or this.
我不知道
I don't... I don't know.
或许你会的
Maybe you would have.
可你就不会了  是不是
But you wouldn't, would you? You wouldn't.
我可以骂你
I could insult you.
什么
What?
档案馆里有很多恶言谩骂
There's tons of invective in the archive.
我总是有话直说  我可以对你说一些
I like speaking my mind, I could throw some of that at you.
滚出我家
Get out of this house.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我不能走出我启动点25米开外
I can't go more than 25 metres from my activation point.
你在开玩笑吗
What is that, a joke?
我知道这很疯狂
Look, I know it sounds mental.
你的启动点在哪
Where's your activation point?
虽然这可能会让你疯掉
At the risk of blowing your mind...
就是我启动的地方
it's where I was activated.
就是浴缸
The bath.
我必须待在浴缸25米半径内  除非我的管理员
I have to keep within a 25-metre radius unless my administrator,
就是你  陪着我走
that's you, is with me.
别说我是你的管理员
Don't call me your administrator.
为什么
Why not?
因为
Because...
听上去挺性感的
It sounds sort of sexy.
你笑了  我能回去吗
If you're laughing, can I come back inside?
我觉得
Feeling a bit...
自己像株观赏植物
ornamental out here.
真好笑
Funny.
能把那个放下吗
Can you put that down, please?
但是很好笑啊
But it is funny.
把那个放下好吗
Could you just put it down?
跟我来  我们出去
Come with me. We're going out.
真俗
Cheesy.
来吧
Come on.
我们去哪
Where are we going?
快走
Just hurry up.
不
No!
别那么做
Don't do it!
真的  别那么做
Seriously, don't do it.
我不会的
I'm not going to.
好吧
Ok.
瞧  他会知道到底是怎么回事
See, he would have worked out what was going on.
虽然我不会这样做  但是如果有这个情况
This wouldn't have ever happened, but if it had,
他会知道的
he would have worked it out.
抱歉  等等  这句话不太好理解
Sorry, hang on. That's a very difficult sentence to process.
跳
Jump.
什么  往那儿跳吗
What? Over there?
我从没有任何自杀或自残倾向
I never expressed suicidal thoughts, or self-harm.
但你不是你啊
Yeah, well, you aren't you, are you?
这句也不太好理解
That's another difficult one, to be honest with you.
你只是你的涟漪  你没有过去
You're just a few ripples of you. There's no history to you.
你只是表演了他未经思考做的一些事
You're just a performance of stuff that he performed without thinking,
这是不够的
and it's not enough.
别这样  我是来取悦你的
Come on. I aim to please.
那就跳吧  跳吧
Aim to jump. Just do it.
好吧
Ok.
如果你确定
If you're absolutely sure.
瞧  艾什会害怕的
See, Ash would've been scared.
他不会就那么跳了  他会哭的
He wouldn't have just leapt off, he would have been crying,
他会...
he would have been...
天呐  不要
Oh... Oh, God, no.
求你  我不想那么做
Please, I don't want to do it.
求你别逼我
Please don't make me do it.
不  这不公平
No. That's not fair.
不  我很害怕  亲爱的  求你
No, I'm... I'm frightened, darling, please...
别逼我
Don't make me.
我不想死啊  天呐  我不想死
I don't want to die. Oh, God, I don't want to die
这不公平
No, that's not fair.
我好怕  我不想死
I'm frightened, I don't want to die. Don't...
不
No!!!!
一块给你  一块给我
One for you, one for me.
怎么了
What?
还得要一片
We need another slice.
为什么
Why?
我好拿上去啊
So I can take one upstairs.
又没到周末
It's not the weekend.
是我生日嘛
It is my birthday.
好吧
Ok.
谢谢  妈妈
"Thanks, Mum."
艾什
Hey, Ash.
小寿星
Hey. The birthday girl.
我来跟你待一会儿
Just gonna come and hang out for a bit.
好啊  反正我也没做什么
OK. I wasn't doing anything.
我给你拿蛋糕了
I brought you some cake.
我知道你不吃东西
I know you don't eat anything.
其实我就是用你做借口想多吃一块
I'm just using you as an excuse so I can get an extra slice.
真坏啊
Devious.
妈妈
Mum?
Mum!
我就来了
Yeah, I'm just coming.